

# **Lyubomir Ganev**

**E-mail:** luboganev@gmail.com **Website:** https://luboganev.dev

## **About me**

I am a software engineer focused on native Android development. Through the years I have worked also in other areas of the software development like desktop applications and backend and frontend web development. I am curious and enjoy learning and trying out new technologies while doing some programming during my free time.

# **Personal Skills & Competences**

Software Technologies Programming Languages: Kotlin, Java, Swift.

**Frameworks:** Android SDK, Bluetooth, BLE, Gradle, Firebase, Fabric, Crashlytics, Sentry, Answers, Play Services, HockeyApp / AppCenter.

**Libraries:** Ktor, Kotlin multiplatform, Coroutines, Support Library, Android Jetpack, Jeptack Compose, Picasso, Coil, Lottie, Butterknife, RxJava 1 & 2, RxAndroid, Arrow, Koin, Dagger 1 & 2, Hilt, Retrofit 1 & 2, Timber, OkHttp, Gson, Moshi, Parceler, Realm, JUnit, Mockito, Roboelectric, Espresso.

**Web Technologies:** HTTP, REST, XML, JSON, HTML, CSS, Regex, REST, Markdown, Jekyll.

Version Controlling: Git, Git Flow, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Stash, SVN.

Continuous Integration: Jenkins, TeamCity, CircleCI

Databases Technologies: RoomDB, Realm, MySQL, SQLite.

Operating Systems: Mac OS, Android, Windows, Linux.

**Programming Environments:** Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ Idea, XCode, Brackets, Atom.

**Other Competences:** Clean, VIPER, MVP, MVVM, Reactive programming, Functional programming, Open Source, Code Reviews, Pair Programming, Stack Overflow, Slack, Skype, Scrum, Kanban, Agile, JIRA, Confluence.

Languages

**Bulgarian** - Native language **English** - Fluent (Level C1).

German - Fluent (Level C1).

# **Work Experience**

## Jan 2022 - Today

## **IU International University**

Munich, Germany

#### Senior Android developer

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps in the online education area.

#### Mar 2019 - Dec 2021

## **Automotive startup**

Munich, Germany

#### **Lead Android developer**

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps in the smart connected automobiles area.

#### Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

#### **Luxoft GmbH**

Munich, Germany

#### **Technical Lead Android**

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps in the automotive environment.

#### Sep 2016 - Aug 2018

## **Bragi GmbH**

Munich, Germany

#### **Technical Lead Android**

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps, in-house prototypes and SDK for third parties.

## July 2014 - Aug 2016

# **Jochen Schweizer Technology Solutions GmbH**

Munich, Germany

#### **Mobile Developer**

Development of native Android and iOS Apps.

## Dec 2013 - June 2014

## **CHIP Digital GmbH**

Munich, Germany

#### **Android Developer**

Development of native Android and iOS Apps and REST Back-End.

#### May 2012 - Nov 2013

#### 1st Position GmbH

Saarbrücken, Germany

#### **Android Developer**

Development of native Android Apps and REST Back-End.

Mar 2011 - Dec 2011

## Institut für Wirtschaftsinformatik (IWI) bei DFKI GmbH

Saarbrücken, Germany

#### Research assistant

Development of back-end functionality and the front-end mobile user interface part of the uService project. (http://uservices.de/)

Dec 2008 - Oct 2009

#### **Mobiltel EAD**

Sofia, Bulgaria

#### Web developer

Internal and external company web sites and web applications.

## **Education**

Oct 2009 - Mar 2012

## **Saarland University**

Saarbrücken, Germany

#### **MSc Computer Science**

**Subjects covered:** Database systems, Cryptography, Security, Mobile applications development, Innovative Technologies in Retail Environment, Multi- touch interactions, User interface design and usability

**Master Thesis Topic:** Framework for Evaluation of Recommender Systems that Suggest Mobile Applications

Oct 2004 - May 2008

# **Technical University - Sofia**

Sofia, Bulgaria

#### **BSc Computer Science**

**Subjects covered:** OOP, Computer networks, Operating systems, Discrete structures, Algorithms synthesis, Computer graphics

### References

**Publications** 

# AppFunnel: a framework for usage-centric evaluation of recommender systems that suggest mobile applications

Matthias Böhmer, Lyubomir Ganev, Antonio Krüger IUI '13

# AppDetox: helping users with mobile app addiction

Lyubomir Ganev, Matthias Böhmer, Markus Löchtefeld MUM '13

**Projects** 

## **AppDetox**

Android application

AppDetox was developed by the AppDocs team which consists of three researchers/developers including myself. The purpose of the app is to provide heavy Android users with a tool that helps them perform self-control and tame their mobile apps usage on daily basis. Further information available on the official application page in Google Play.

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.dfki.appdetox)

#### Anidro

Android application

Anidro is a fun app which brings motion to static drawings. Users can create simple drawings on their smartphone or tablet and then share an animated version of these drawings as an animated GIF or video. It is an open-source project which highlights some architectural best practices. Further information available on the official application page in Google Play and the GitHub page of the project.

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.anidro) (http://luboganev.dev/anidro/)

## **Further projects**

For more projects please visit my website.

(https://luboganev.dev/about/)